<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Columbia University Libraries Studio</title>
    <description>The Columbia University Libraries Studio is both a space and a practice that enables and promotes ethical, sustainable, FAIR, and collaborative, digital and data-driven research and pedagogy.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:07:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Publishing Open Lab, Mondays 3:00 pm – 5:00 pm</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-publishing-open-lab-mondays-300-pm--500-pm&quot;&gt;Publishing Open Lab, Mondays 3:00 pm – 5:00 pm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open publishing lab is a space for the Columbia community to explore open, ethical publishing practices and tools and build research communication expertise in a respectful, welcoming environment. Come to Studio at Butler (208b) to find your next collaborators and co-conspirators!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a peer review group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Promote an existing publication—or start a new one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment with tools for publishing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find collaborators for your project or publication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Streamline your publication processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your work openly available&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Publish your data or preprint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the word out about your research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop your online presence or digital portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions? publishing@library.columbia.edu Drop in or stay a while!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/open%20lab/2019/02/20/publishing-open-lab-mondays/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/open%20lab/2019/02/20/publishing-open-lab-mondays/</guid>
        
        
        <category>open lab</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peer Review and Pretzels @ Publishing Open Lab</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-peer-review-and-pretzels--publishing-open-lab&quot;&gt;Peer Review and Pretzels @ Publishing Open Lab&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come join us Monday, February 25th at 3pm for a special edition of publishing open lab. Asked to peer review somebody else’s work and don’t know where to start? Worried that you might have to be a peer reviewer some day? We’ll talk through what responsible, ethical peer review looks like, how to provide critical but constructive feedback, and how to get credit for the work you put into the peer review process. Also, pretzels!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open publishing lab is a space for the Columbia community to explore open, ethical publishing practices and tools and build research communication expertise in a respectful, welcoming environment. Come find your next collaborators and co-conspirators!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/open%20lab/2019/02/20/peer-review-pretzels/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/open%20lab/2019/02/20/peer-review-pretzels/</guid>
        
        
        <category>open lab</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Corpus-DB</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us at Studio at Butler on February 20, 2019 at 4:30pm for a presentation by Jonathan Reeve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-corpus-db-a-corpus-generation-framework-for-computational-text-analysis&quot;&gt;Corpus-DB: A Corpus-Generation Framework for Computational Text Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corpus-DB is a textual corpus infrastructure for the digital humanities. It solves perennial problems of text aggregation, cleaning, and categorization that constitute so much of the labor of a text analysis project. Come learn to use Corpus-DB for your project in digital analysis, digital history, or computational social science, or come to learn more about the Corpus-DB project, and how to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-jonathan-reeve&quot;&gt;Jonathan Reeve&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Reeve is a PhD candidate in the Department of English and Comparative Literature at Columbia University, specializing in computational literary analysis, cultural analytics, and data-driven approaches to literary criticism. His recent projects include Open Editions, open-source, semantically annotated scholarly editions of literary texts; Git-Lit, an applicaiton of distributed version control towards the creation of 50,000 scholarly editions; and Macro-Etym, software for analysis of textual macro-etymologies. His most recent publication include include “A Macro-Etymological Analysis of James Joyce’s &lt;em&gt;A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man&lt;/em&gt;” in &lt;em&gt;Reading Modernism with Machines&lt;/em&gt; (Palgrave Macmillan, 2016) and “Open Editions Online,” forthcoming in &lt;em&gt;James Joyce Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2019/02/13/corpus-db-studio-presentation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/02/13/corpus-db-studio-presentation/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Love Data Week 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Get involved in this week’s &lt;a href=&quot;#s-postcard-project&quot;&gt;Postcard Project&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;#s-love-data-week-2019-instagram-challenge&quot;&gt;Love Data
Week 2019 Instagram Challenge&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;#s-love-data-photobooths&quot;&gt;Love Data Photobooths&lt;/a&gt;, and,
finally, &lt;a href=&quot;#s-love-data-kisses&quot;&gt;Love Data Kisses&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February 11–15 is not only Columbia’s annual week of &lt;a href=&quot;https://universitylife.columbia.edu/wellness-days-columbia-schedule&quot;&gt;Wellness
Days&lt;/a&gt;
activities, but it also marks &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovedataweek.org/&quot;&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;. At
the Studio, we support both wellness and loving data, and we are teaming up
with our colleagues in the Columbia University Libraries to provide some
activities that generate public data in the interest of this year’s Love Data
Week theme, “data in everyday life.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-postcard-project&quot;&gt;Postcard Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Libraries are letting you send postcards to your loved ones around the
world this week. At nine Columbia Libraries
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/avery.html&quot;&gt;Avery&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/burke.html&quot;&gt;Burke&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/butler.html&quot;&gt;Butler&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/journalism.html&quot;&gt;Journalism&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/lehman.html&quot;&gt;Lehman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/science-engineering.html&quot;&gt;Science and
Engineering&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/social-work.html&quot;&gt;Social Work&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/business.html&quot;&gt;Watson&lt;/a&gt;), you will be
able to fill out postcards, and Columbia Libraries will pick up the postage.
In exchange, we’ll be keeping track of what states and countries the postcards
are addressed to, and we’re building a world map of places our community is
reaching out to this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;love-data-map-19&quot; style=&quot;height: 50vh&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;love-data-map-19-legend&quot; class=&quot;mb-3 w-100&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-love-data-week-2019-instagram-challenge&quot;&gt;Love Data Week 2019 Instagram Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the Science, Engineering, and Social Sciences Libraries Division
(SESSL) is organizing an Instagram Challenge. Throughout their five libraries
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/journalism.html&quot;&gt;Journalism&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/lehman.html&quot;&gt;Lehman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/science-engineering.html&quot;&gt;Science and
Engineering&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/social-work.html&quot;&gt;Social Work&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/business.html&quot;&gt;Watson&lt;/a&gt;), they have
placed large Valentines. Your goal is to photograph yourself in front of one
and then post it to Instagram, hashtagged
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/lovedata19/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#LoveData19&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/lovecolumbia/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#LoveColumbia&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll
give out gift cards to three lucky winners: first, best, and “other.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the week, we’ll build a data visualization of when the competing
stories were posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-love-data-photobooths&quot;&gt;Love Data Photobooths&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SESSL is also organizing an opportunity to have you pose in their
photobooths to announce your support of open data and the Libraries.
One booth will be in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/lehman.html&quot;&gt;Lehman&lt;/a&gt; all week. The
other one will be roaming around the other SESSL Libraries,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/burke.html&quot;&gt;Burke&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/butler.html&quot;&gt;Butler&lt;/a&gt;. Both will be at
Butler in on Thursday evening during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.columbia.edu/cal/event/eventView.do?b=de&amp;amp;calPath=%2Fpublic%2Fcals%2FMainCal&amp;amp;guid=CAL-00bb9e25-68a32c67-0168-a4614696-00000965events@columbia.edu&amp;amp;recurrenceId=&quot;&gt;Night @
Butler&lt;/a&gt; event, from 7:00pm to 9:00pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full schedule for roaming photobooth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/burke.html&quot;&gt;Burke&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/science-engineering.html&quot;&gt;Science and Engineering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/social-work.html&quot;&gt;Social
Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;: Burke, Science and Engineering, Social Work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;: Burke, &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/journalism.html&quot;&gt;Journalism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/locations/business.html&quot;&gt;Watson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;: Burke, Butler, Journalism, Watson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-love-data-kisses&quot;&gt;Love Data Kisses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are chocolate kisses floating around this week from the
Libraries and from the open data community. Find them and enjoy them, either
by sharing them with loved ones or keeping them all to yourself. Or something
in between.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2019/02/05/love-data-week-2019-01/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/02/05/love-data-week-2019-01/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spring at Studio at Butler</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A new year brings a new semester, which also means new events at &lt;a href=&quot;/spaces/butler&quot;&gt;Studio at
Butler&lt;/a&gt;. This semester, we will continue to
offer an &lt;a href=&quot;/open-lab.html&quot;&gt;Open Lab&lt;/a&gt; every Friday, 3–5pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Studio at Butler is introducing Open Labs on Mondays, as well,
beginning February 4. Facilitated by Digital Publishing Librarian Michelle
Wilson and Assistant Director of Scholarly Communication and Projects Nicky
Agate, these Open Labs will be focused on academic publishing and scholarly
communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late March, Digital Scholarship Librarian Alex Gil and
GIS/Metadata Librarian Eric Glass will be leading a four-part mini-course on
the geographical representation of bibliographical data. Stay tuned for a more
in-depth description of the four sessions in the upcoming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studio at Butler will also continue its tradition of being a digital
laboratory attached to a seminar or a collaborative space for regular,
scheduled use. This semester, Studio at Butler will be used by Professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://history.columbia.edu/faculty/smith-pamela-h/&quot;&gt;Pamela
Smith&lt;/a&gt;, Associate
Professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://english.columbia.edu/people/profile/453&quot;&gt;Dennis Tenen&lt;/a&gt;, the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://c4sr.columbia.edu&quot;&gt;Center for Spatial Research&lt;/a&gt;, and the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://edblogs.columbia.edu/musiconis/&quot;&gt;FAB-Musiconis project&lt;/a&gt; under the
direction of Professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://music.columbia.edu/bios/susan-boynton&quot;&gt;Susan
Boynton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we hope to finalize our guest speaker schedule and make an
announcement soon about bringing some exciting voices in cultural analytics,
experimental and mobilized humanities, social justice, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/workshop/open%20lab/2019/01/25/spring-at-butler-2019-01/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/workshop/open%20lab/2019/01/25/spring-at-butler-2019-01/</guid>
        
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
        <category>open lab</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NYCDH Week at the Studio</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As it has for every year since &lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org&quot;&gt;NYCDH Week&lt;/a&gt; began,
the Studio is hosting workshops among the myriad opportunities to learn more
about digital humanities around New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we’re taking advantage of the new Studio, Studio at Lehman, to push
our number of workshops to the limit. The Studio will be hosting seven
Columbia-related workshops, and we invite you to come participate in as many
as you like. Specific information and RSVP links are available in the sidebar,
but below, we’ll describe each workshop in a bit of detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the workshops below are for beginners except for one, and you should
bring a laptop to the workshops if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org/event/introduction-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Introduction to
Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Digital
Scholarship Librarian and Studio founder Alex Gil will be leading the first of
two workshops Tuesday morning during NYCDH Week. In this workshop he will
offer an introduction to the static website generator
&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is used to make fast, durable, loading
webpages or projects. Jekyll has been used for many genres of academic work:
digital editions, academic journals, digital archives of images and more. If
you ever wanted to create a website that you control and design, this is the
workshop for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org/event/make-a-simple-webmap-with-leaflet/&quot;&gt;Make a Simple Webmap with
Leaflet&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;
Research Data Librarian Moacir P. de Sá Pereira will lead an introduction to
JavaScript by also showing how to use the web-mapping library
&lt;a href=&quot;http://leafletjs.com&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of the workshop, users will be
able to embed maps in webpages using data they provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org/event/working-with-open-data-intro-to-apis-2/&quot;&gt;Working with Open Data: Intro to
APIs&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;
There is so much data out on the web that knowing how to use APIs will let you
explore and collect that data in a reliable and efficient way. This workshop
will be taught by Amir Imani, a student at the Data Science Institute and a
grantee at the Brown Institute for Media Innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org/event/advanced-topics-in-word-embeddings/&quot;&gt;Advanced Topics in Word
Embeddings&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;
PhD Candidate Jonathan Reeve will lead a workshop on advanced topics in word
embeddings. Word embeddings are the hottest new technology in natural language
processing, and are used across linguistic computer science, from machine
translation to information extraction and computational literary analysis. We
will cover advanced topics in word embeddings, including: document similarity
analysis, nearest-neighbor analysis, training vector spaces, and
visualization. We will use literary texts as examples, but the methods are
applicable across disciplines, and participants are encouraged to bring their
own corpora to analyze. Python will be our workshop language, and we will use
the libraries &lt;a href=&quot;http://spacy.io&quot;&gt;SpaCy&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word2vec&quot;&gt;Word2Vec&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/explosion/sense2vec&quot;&gt;Sense2Vec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please bring a laptop on which you’ve installed the Python libraries SpaCy,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://scikit-learn.org/stable/&quot;&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pandas.pydata.org/&quot;&gt;pandas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matplotlib.org/&quot;&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;,
word2vec, and sense2vec, as well as the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;en_core_web_lg&lt;/code&gt; language model. Check
that you can load it successfully with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;spacy.load('en_core_web_lg')&lt;/code&gt;. Refer
to the SpaCy documentation for instructions on installing the language model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org/event/simple-cv/&quot;&gt;Simple-CV&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; NYCDH Week
coincides with the first week of the &lt;a href=&quot;/workshop/2019/01/04/write-in-plain-text-with-scholartxt-2019-01/&quot;&gt;Scholar.txt&lt;/a&gt; workshop
series, so the first workshop, on making an online and print CV from the same
plain text file, has been rolled into the NYCDH Week festivities. Moacir will
be leading this workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org/event/introduction-to-github-for-scholars/&quot;&gt;Introduction to GitHub for
Scholars&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;
In this workshop, Research Computing Program Coordinator Patrick Smyth will
introduce &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.git-scm.com&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Git,
a distributed version control system, and GitHub, a service for storing code
in the cloud, are frequently used together to preserve data, collaborate in
teams, and discover tools and code written by others. This workshop will
introduce you to Git’s primary functionality, which includes tracking,
altering, and sharing the history of a project. It will also discuss use cases
for Git and GitHub that include managing CVs, notes, and course syllabuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dhweek.nycdh.org/event/git-and-atom/&quot;&gt;Git and Atom&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Moacir closes
the Columbia NYCDH Week workshops with an second introduction to
&lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.org&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, teaching how to use Git to put your projects,
articles, and chapters under version control. Then, see how easy it is to
integrate Git with &lt;a href=&quot;http://atom.io&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, a hackable text editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/workshop/2019/01/21/nycdh-week-2019-01/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/workshop/2019/01/21/nycdh-week-2019-01/</guid>
        
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Year, New Studio</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Coming soon &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/studioatbutler?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#studioatbutler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;— Alex Gil (@elotroalex) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elotroalex/status/368817038828908546?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 17, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the Columbia University Libraries’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://library.columbia.edu/locations/dhc.html&quot;&gt;Digital Humanities
Center&lt;/a&gt;, along
with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://teachingcenter.wikischolars.columbia.edu/&quot;&gt;Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Teaching
Center&lt;/a&gt;, established
“Studio@Butler,” which they described as a space “&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/news/libraries/2013/2013-9-11_Studio_Butler_Opens.html&quot;&gt;designed to support emerging
practices in pedagogy and digital
scholarship&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot has changed in five years, with the continued growth of digital,
data-driven research across disciplines as one exponent of that change. The
Studio has grown and changed as well, as it fell under the purview of &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/services/digital-scholarship/&quot;&gt;Digital
Scholarship&lt;/a&gt;.
Programming has included the 2017 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/02/nyregion/maps-puerto-rico-hurricane-maria.html&quot;&gt;Puerto Rico
Mapathon&lt;/a&gt;,
where the Studio was too small to hold the 25 librarians helping over 60
volunteers to improve maps of Puerto Rico in the aftermath of Hurricane Maria.
In addition, the Studio has hosted a Friday afternoon Open Lab, where the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://xpmethod.plaintext.in&quot;&gt;Group for Experimental Methods in Humanistic Research at Columbia
University&lt;/a&gt; has traditionally gathered, that has
generated innovative digital, data-driven research. Finally, through its
invited talks and general welcoming ethos, the Studio has welcomed researchers
from universities around the world to discuss their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, it became increasingly clear that the Studio was not just an
experimental space but a space central to Columbia University Libraries’ core &lt;a href=&quot;https://strategicdirections.library.columbia.edu/&quot;&gt;strategic
directions&lt;/a&gt;. The
ahierarchical structure of the Open Lab aims to foster inclusion as a founding
principle, making use of that inclusion to inspire inquiry, catalyze
discovery, and advance knowledge. Through its work looking outward to the
world beyond Columbia’s walls, the Studio has empowered staff and helped shape
discourse around pressing issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This alignment of values implied that others within the Libraries were doing similar
work in fostering digital, data-driven research and pedagogy that was
simultaneously ethical, sustainable, and collaborative. And so, the Studio is
now growing with its first sibling Studio, the space maintained by &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.columbia.edu/services/research-data-services.html&quot;&gt;Research
Data
Services&lt;/a&gt;,
which has been running its own Open Labs four times a week with nearly
identical commitments. As such the Studio now spans two Libraries divisions, Digital
Scholarship and the Science, Engineering, and Social Sciences Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Studio, then, is both a space and a practice. A space for innovative
scholarly work done within a practice of inclusion. But just as the practice
is built from several core principles, the space is also built from more than
one site. Studio at Lehman now joins Studio at Butler, sharing programming,
principles, and this very webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this webpage, we hope that it grows alongside the Studio. In addition to
the information about programming included in the earlier version of the site,
this new one will also include programming at Studio at Lehman alongside
programming of note outside of the Studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, as the Studio is not just a space for programming but also a
practice, we will grow our library of tuition, creating workshops and
tutorials as well as sharing others we encounter. We find that scholars with
principles similar to ours are often left adrift by typical digital,
data-driven tuition, which can be narrowly tool- and results-oriented.
Instead, we foreground ethical, sustainable, and collaborative digital,
data-driven research and pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new year 2019 promises great things, and we hope you’ll join us for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/article/2019/01/05/new-year-new-studio-2019-01/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/article/2019/01/05/new-year-new-studio-2019-01/</guid>
        
        
        <category>article</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Write in Plain Text with the Scholar.txt Workshop Series</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Columbia University Libraries Studio’s 2019 workshops kick off with a
four-session series, “Scholar.txt.” Writing with plain text can make your
research and scholarship more available, sustainable, and ethical.
Nevertheless, it goes against inertial orthodoxy in terms of scholarly
production, especially in the humanities and social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the four sessions, we will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a CV that becomes a webpage and well-formatted pdf with one command,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write a scholarly article using plain text and managing citations,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share and discuss our experiences with learning how to use plain text in a
scholarly environment, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contribute to the open pedagogy for plain text scholarship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sessions are independent and require no prior knowledge. They will include
introductions and/or make use of the following freely available software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://atom.io&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, a plain text editor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pandoc.org&quot;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;, a universal document converter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, a version control application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zotero.org&quot;&gt;Zotero&lt;/a&gt;, a reference management application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ctan.org&quot;&gt;TeX, LaTeX, and XeLaTeX&lt;/a&gt;, a suite of document typesetting
applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sessions will be lead by our research data librarian, Moacir P. de Sá
Pereira, with assistance from other members of the Columbia University
Libraries Studio community. Come join us and learn to make your work
available, sustainable, and ethical.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/workshop/2019/01/04/write-in-plain-text-with-scholartxt-2019-01/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/workshop/2019/01/04/write-in-plain-text-with-scholartxt-2019-01/</guid>
        
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Media and Paranoia w/ Clemens Apprich (Leuphana University)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Clemens Apprich is visiting research fellow at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalemergentmedia.com&quot;&gt;Global Emergent Media
Lab&lt;/a&gt; at Concordia University in Montréal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will speak about his current research project, which examines the
reciprocity between paranoia and media. Building on the work started in his
previous monograph, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20181028190138/https://www.rowmaninternational.com/book/technotopia/3-156-79eda6dd-49eb-4b7e-8586-cc3c6263c729&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technotopia: A Media Genealogy of Net
Cultures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(Rowman 2017), Apprich employs the rich discourse around paranoia—ranging
from the history of psychiatry, film and literature studies, to media
theory—to explore the ‘sub-medial spaces’ which are all too often excluded
from our analysis of cultural, social and political practices in relation to
digital technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/events/2018/12/10/clemens-apprich/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/events/2018/12/10/clemens-apprich/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Just Digitization: Opportunities for Image Processing in Digital Humanities&quot; with Melissa Terras</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us at the Butler Studio on November 15, 2018 at 4PM for a talk by Melissa Terras on new work on visual culture and computational possibilities. This event is organized by Digital Scholarship at Columbia Libraries and co-sponsored by xpMethod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;s-just-digitization-opportunities-for-image-processing-in-digital-humanities&quot;&gt;Just Digitization: Opportunities for Image Processing in Digital Humanities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Digital Humanities activity revolves around text and textual processing, although there are more and more opportunities to use 2D and 3D imaging approaches applied to primary historical sources to enable their analysis. In this talk, Terras will talk about the research relationship between the computational and engineering sciences and the cultural heritage community, and provide an overview of various projects which have seen the adoption and adaption of digitisation techniques which require data processing and analysis. What can we borrow from the computational sciences when imaging historical materials, but what can we also contribute? From the reconstruction of individual damaged texts, to the scanning of whole museums, and the intersection of machine learning and manuscript studies, Terras will discuss what it means to operate successfully in this interdisciplinary space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-melissa-terras&quot;&gt;Melissa Terras&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melissa Terras is the Professor of Digital Cultural Heritage at the University of Edinburgh‘s College of Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences, leading digital aspects of research within CAHSS, and Director of Research in the new Edinburgh Futures Institute. Her research focuses on the use of computational techniques to enable research in the arts, humanities, and wider cultural heritage and information environment that would otherwise be impossible. She is an Honorary Professor of Digital Humanities in UCL Department of Information Studies, where she was employed from 2003-2017. Books include “Image to Interpretation: An Intelligent System to Aid Historians in Reading the Vindolanda Texts” (2006, Oxford University Press), “Defining Digital Humanities: A Reader” (Ashgate 2013) and “Picture-Book Professors: Academia and Children’s Literature” (Cambridge University Press 2018). She is a Fellow of the Alan Turing Institute, Trustee of the National Library of Scotland, and currently serves on the Board of Curators of the University of Oxford Libraries. You can generally find her on twitter @melissaterras.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/events/2018/11/15/melissa-terras/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/events/2018/11/15/melissa-terras/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
